Rajat Dhiman

Hayward, CA, 94544

Contact Number: +1(510) 203-8942

E-mail:rdsocials113@outlook.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajatdhiman3/

Professional Summary

Dedicated Engineering & Technical Program Manager, Process Improvement Specialist with over 7 years of experience in the OEM EMS space. KPI and outcome focused professional with the history of meeting company goals utilizing using all available resources. adaptive problem solver and high-performer under pressure, challenges to best enhance the organizational brand.

Skills

Al, Electronics Manufacturing, Benchmarking, Agile, Scrum, Team and Technical Leadership, Design and Process Engineering, Communication, Product Vision, Strategic leadership, Quality Assurance, Technical Customer Relationship Management, Process Engineering, Quality Engineering, Systems Engineering, PDLC, SPC, DFX, Continuous Improvement, Documentation proficiency

Experience

Technical Program Manager

Jun. 2022 – Present

Unigen Corporation

Newark, CA

- Technical program management and engineering management for Edge AI server and E1.S form factor 48 TOPS TPU modules
- Fully managed and owned New Product Introduction (NPI) build operations pipeline, build timelines, milestones
- Launched, and drove a team of design and validation engineers to launch brand new product lines including Compute eXpress Link, Non Volatile Random Access Memory, Storage accelerators and launching products in 3-6 month development cycles
- Drove product design for existing Client and Enterprise products form 'Product specification' to 'Product realization' to scale and support
 Purchase Orders for existing product lines Solid state Drives, DRAM and Non Volatile Dual Inline Memory Modules for existing and
 next-gen products
- Spearheaded and improved DVT reports by defining SLAs using industrial standards, ISO procedures and technical reviews with owners, while also improving report Turnaround time using Lean Six Sigma, Agile project management techniques, Atlassian toolsets, reducing review and handover, and context switching time from 2 hours to 15 minutes on weekly reviews
- Defined and created workflows using JIRA Work Management, Confluence and Smartsheet project management systems to strengthen agile program management based project realization in both software and H/W development. Developed technical collateral based on process and organizational document control flows to ensure integration to ISO requirements to ensure effectiveness, reliability and efficient scaling of Cross Functional Team systems across the organization
- Organized and implemented regular design and quality reviews with ISVs, IHVs, SOC Chip, Memory and DRAM partners, test equipment vendors, customers ensuring projects and timelines are measured and managed accurately. Leading into delivery of 8 successful technical programs with over \$ 20 million in revenue
- Served as a technical liaison between Customer, Engineering, Marketing, Supply Chain, Operations during Design and new product introduction engineers, build work flows to effectively communicate requirements and resolve technical conflicts ensuring program health
- Managed firmware release and qualification by maintaining release notes, errata, Engineering Change Notifications through development and coordinating Product Control Notifications to customers as required
- Ensured stakeholder accountability and task visibility with regular project plan review, cross functional team meetings, follow-ups, escalations
- Prompt engineered with AI tools such as Google Bard and Open AI Chat GPT to speed up creating and reviewing Legal, Engineering and Product Marketing Collateral reducing cycle time from 2 weeks to few days

Sr. Technical Program Manager, Process Engineer

Aug. 2018 – Jun. 2022

SMART Modular Technologies

Newark, CA

- Delivered programs valued at approximately \$10 million in sales for specialty memory business unit
- Managed cross functional projects in matrix organization covering range of areas to provide network connectivity to developing areas worldwide
- Achieved overall 29% cycle time reduction by implementing ground-up JIRA frameworks and 'one-step-ahead' meetings across multiple cross-functional teams
- Scheduled, risk and change management on different NPI accounts related to product design in coordination with various engineering management
- · Implemented effective program communication and visibility to all internal and external stakeholders
- Championed program management, lean six-sigma and operational excellence, also establishing metrics for measuring performance and improvements in these areas

Aug. 2018 – Jun. 2022

Education

Master of Science: Industrial and Systems Engineering

State University of New York at Binghamton

Jul. 2016 – Aug. 2018 Binghamton, NY

Bachelor of Technology

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Aug. 2012 – Jul. 2016 New Delhi, India